Guide to the Bruce Ferrini paleography collection, circa 4000 B.C.-1800.
Ferrini, Bruce paleography collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Bruce Ferrini paleography collection, circa 4000 B.C.-1800.
4671
Ferrini, Bruce P.,
2 Cubic Feet.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Examples of various historical writing systems and scripts, including hieroglyphics on fragments of papyrus, reed sticks with proto-Arabian inscriptions, cuneiform tablets, a bowl inscribed in Etruscan, Aramaic incantation bowls, a bronze piece with a runic inscription, Arabic on cloth fragments, decorated 13th-century Bible leaves, and other writings through the 18th century.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Examples of various historical writing systems and scripts, including hieroglyphics on fragments of papyrus, reed sticks with proto-Arabian inscriptions, cuneiform tablets, a bowl inscribed in Etruscan, Aramaic incantation bowls, a bronze piece with a runic inscription, Arabic on cloth fragments, decorated 13th-century Bible leaves, and other writings through the 18th century.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ferrini, Bruce P.
Subjects:
Paleography -- Study and teaching.; Hieroglyphics.; Runes.; Cuneiform inscriptions.; Etruscan language; Aramaic language; Manuscripts, Medieval.
Form and Genre Terms:
Texts
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Cuneiform tablets, 2500-2000 BCE (Box 8)
- Fragment of the Book of the Dead, hieroglyphics on papyrus, circa 1500 BCE (Box 1)
- Three papyrus fragments with hieratic inscriptions, circa 1000 BCE (Box 1)
- Three papyrus fragments with demotic inscriptions, circa 700 BCE (Box 2)
- Egyptian seal with hieroglyphics inscription, circa 1000 BCE (Box 7)
- Egyptian hieratic inscription on linen, circa 1000 BCE (Box 6)
- Egyptian hieratic inscription on linen, circa 1000 BCE (Box 10)
- Three papyrus fragments with Coptic inscriptions, 1st-6th century CE (Box 3)
- Three papyrus fragments with Greek inscriptions, 1st-6th century CE (Box 4)
- Three Aramaic inscriptions on lead, 2nd-5th century CE (Box 5)
- Three birch bark fragments from the "Dead Sea Scrolls of Buddhism", 3rd-5th century CE (Box 6)
- Medieval period Runic inscription on metal fragment (Box 10)
- Three leaf books, "The 13th century Bible", original leaves enclosed, 13th century CE (Box 6)
- Two Arabic fragments on linen, circa 16th century CE (Box 10)
- More than 60 manuscript leaves in Arabic. Religious and secular texts, 17th-19th century CE (Box 10)
- Etruscan bowl with inscription (Box 7)
- Pottery vessel with unknown inscription (Box 7)
- Mummy cartonnage fragment with text imbedded, circa 1000 BCE (Box 8)
- Three South Arabian inscribed sticks (Box 8)
- Petrified reed with Arabic legal inscription (Box 7)
- Three incantation bowls with Aramaic inscriptions, circa 5th century BCE (Box 9)
- Three Navajo mnemonic drawings, 19th century CE (Box 5)
- Round metal item with Greek inscription inlay (Box 7)
- Fragment of the Book of Exodus, in Greek, 4th century BCE (Box 6)